<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Alexander Techniek Opleiding Nederland</title>
    <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Alexander Techniek Opleiding Nederland</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:48:43 +0200</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>ATON</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/home/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:48:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/home/</guid>
      <description>On this site you will find information on training to become a teacher of the Alexander Technique, at the Alexander Techniek Opleiding Nederland (ATON) training course, situated in a suburb of Amsterdam called Amstelveen.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Teachers Training</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/opleiding/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/opleiding/</guid>
      <description>The objective of the training-course is first and formost the training of people wishing to become a teacher of the Alexander Technique. At the same time it is possible for people, who have lessons, to visit the course in order to deepen into the Technique, say for some days or any other length of time, without wanting to become a teacher. ATON offers also regularly, get togethers.
The Process First: The training program enables the student to teach in an independent, trustful, explorative and open manner of teaching.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Admission, Design and Costs</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/toelating-opzet-kosten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:46:40 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/toelating-opzet-kosten/</guid>
      <description>Are you motivated to follow the training to become an Alexander Technique teacher and to use it for your personal development? Are you at least 21 years old and have at least 15 lessons experience recently with the Technique? If so, we like to get to know you better.
Admission to the training At first we will invite you to come and taste for 3 or 4 days, the training-course, then the admission procedure consist of a personal talk, some private lessons and the filling in of a questionnaire.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Main Teachers</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/docenten/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:48:43 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/docenten/</guid>
      <description>Arie Jan Hoorweg is founder and director of Alexander Techniek Opleiding Nederland
 I followed the 3 year training-course in London from 1975 untill 1977 inclusive with Walter* and Dilys Carrington. After my training I was teaching privately for 9 years when I started in January 1987 the training-course for teachers-to-be in Holland. Besides my work as a teacher-trainer on ATON, I teach yearly on different training-courses in South-America. Further along do I teach privately (at my home) in Amstelveen, Alkmaar and Utrecht.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>About the Alexander Technique</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/over-alexander-techniek/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/over-alexander-techniek/</guid>
      <description>One has to make a change in the manner of use to raise the standerd of general functioning. — F.M. Alexander (1869-1955)
 De Alexander Technique owes its name to its founder, the Australian F.M. Alexander. He worked as a recital artist until he was no longer able to do his job due to voice problems. No doctor was able to familiarize him with this problem, other than taking a rest, which did not help.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Individual Lessons</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/individuele-lessen/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/individuele-lessen/</guid>
      <description>Alexander had found a method applicable to most common problems of daily life: the problem of habitual misuse of the self, of thoughtlessness. — Walter Carrington MSI 1996
 From a lost/reduced psycho-physical balance to effortless movement We often get so caught up by the fast and busy lives that we hardly spend any more time on ourselves. This leads to that we become aware (too)late when our bodies literally suffers from stress and/or overload.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>More Information</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/meer-informatie/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:54:54 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/meer-informatie/</guid>
      <description>Books by F.M. Alexander:
“Man’s Supreme Inheritance”
F.M. Alexander
ISBN 09525574-0-1
Constructive Conscious Control of the Individual
F.M. Alexander
ISBN 0575-03938-8
The Use of the Self by F.M. Alexander
ISBN 0-575 03720-2
The Universal Constant in Living
F.M. Alexander
ISBN 0-9525574-4-4
Alexander Technique Bookshop: www.alexandertechnique.com/bookshop
Backpain study: http://www.nevlat.nl/wp-content/uploads/2011/09/bmj-article.pdf
The Dutch professional society: **NeVLAT **
www.alexandertechniek.nl
English society : STAT
www.stat.org.uk
Bekijk ook eens deze video’s over de Alexander Techniek van DavidReedMedia op YouTube</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Oct 2018 21:41:37 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://www.alexandertechnique.nl/en/contact/</guid>
      <description>Location The school is situated in a quiet and a lot of green quarter of Amstelveen, a suburb to Amsterdam. With good public transport and car (free parking), it is within easy reach.
Addresss Straat van Gibraltar 34 1183 GW Amstelveen
Telefoon: + 31(0)20-645 29 16 e-mail alexandertechniek@hoorweg.demon.nl
Openbaar Vervoer: Get to Amsterdam Zuid/WTC and take tram 5 in the direction of Amstelveen-Binnenhof, get of at the stop Zonnestein. Cross the tramrails and walk to the roundabout in the short distance, go straight across it and after the supermarket turn right.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>